pokegym.net 2007-12-17

# The PokeGym PokéGym Privacy Statement

**Privacy Policy**

Effective March 1, 2006  
Also see [PokéGym Rules of Conduct.](http://pokegym.net/forums/showthread.php?t=51)

Team Compendium’s PokéGym Web sites and Forums ("this Web site" or "our Web site"), located at [http://pokegym.net](http://www.pokegym.net/) , is operated by Team Compendium ("TC", “PokéGym”, or "we"). Team Compendium brings you this Web site as the unofficial resource for players and organizers of the Pokémon trading card game ("TCG") organized play events (tournaments etc.) and collectors. One of its main purposes is to provide Pokémon TCG players with services including news, rulings, event information, and trading and pricing resources in addition to forums for the discussion of same.

In the course of providing you these services, we may request, record and collect certain information about you, including personal information. While our software systems provide reasonable role-based access control, please be advised that these controls, described in part below, do not guarantee nor promise the confidentiality of your information. Further, these systems provide you with the means to disclose many types of information in ways that we have no control over (such as public message posting or sending a personal message to someone who may then choose to save and/or retransmit that message). You agree that TC and the PokéGym staff are in no way liable in the event of information disclosure for any reason. In addition, you recognize that PokéGym staff are granted access access to all profile information and message content for purposes related to administration of these web sites and message systems. 

**What does this Privacy Policy apply to?**

Please note that the practices set forth in this Privacy Policy apply to users of all ages, including children under 13 years old ("children" or "child"). If a certain policy differs for children under 13, we make a note of it below.

This Privacy Policy currently applies our web sites at [http://pokegym.net](http://pokegym.net/) and sites at URLs within the pokegym.net domain. This Privacy Policy does not apply to web sites operated by other companies or organizations to which we link. When you follow a link to these sites or any other sites not operated by PokéGym from this web site, this Privacy Policy no longer applies. We encourage you to read the privacy policy of the web site to which you link before you submit any personal information to that site.   
Please note that by using our web site, you signify your assent to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use our web site. We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. Please check back from time to time to ensure that you are aware of these changes. If we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by announcing the change on main web site. Your continued use of our web site will signify your acceptance of these changes. 

**What types of information does PokéGym collect and how will it be used?**

In order to give you the best experience on this web site, we may collect certain information about you. You will be asked to submit personal and/or demographic information if you decide to register for the forums or access certain content.

Registration is required to:

  * View certain Forums on our Message Board
  * View most images in our Gallery, and some other content on our web site.
  * Participate in promotions (e.g., contests, free giveaways, etc.)
  * Vote in Polls
  * Correspond with PokéGym staff and other members via e-mail or Private Message.
  * Post messages and replies on our Message Board Forums.

Please note that before you can use the features above, you will be required to register (and, if you are a child under 13, get your parent's prior verifiable and written consent). The specific types of information requested for each activity and the way the information is subsequently used are discussed in greater detail below. 

**Web Site Registration ("PokéGym" Account)**

To create a PokéGym account, you will need to register. As part of registration, we ask you to provide contact information such as your e-mail address. We will also ask you to create a username and password and to provide other information such as your age/date of birth, gender, hobbies and interests (collectively, "demographic information"). When signing up, you are given the opportunity to customize your registration preferences.

For a child under 13 to register, we request essentially the same information listed above, in addition to information about the child's parent, including the parent's name, e-mail address, phone number, and mailing address. We will only collect this information if it is provided voluntarily by the parent or child on our Parental Consent Form and with the parent's verifiable and written consent. To determine who is younger than 13 years old and therefore requires parental consent, we ask all users who wish to register to first tell us their age or date of birth. Registrants who indicate they are under 13 years old are directed to our Parental Consent Form. 

PokéGym uses the information gathered during the registration process to communicate with you, on a more individual level. We may use your information to respond to an inquiry or request by or to contact you about your member status (including inquiries concerning alleged violations of PokéGym rules or other concerns about your participation on the PokéGym). 

**Promotions**

From time to time, TC may run contests, giveaways, or other promotions ("promotions") on our Web site and collect certain information in connection with these promotions. The information collected may include your name, e-mail address, mailing address, phone number and birth date, which is then used to determine your entry eligibility, contact you with the results, and (if applicable) send you a prize. However, in some instances, you may be required to register before you can participate in a promotion. If a child under 13 is allowed to participate, we will either obtain the necessary parental consent or operate the promotion in such a way that parental consent is not required. For more on promotions, please see the rules and regulations accompanying each promotion. 

**Community Features**

As part of the benefits of registration, you will be given access to the PokéGym message boards. To use these features, you are required to register and provide us the information required for registration, in addition to providing information about the hardware you own and other forum settings. While we strive to protect those who wish to participate in these activities through monitoring and moderation, we cannot guarantee the security of, and are not responsible for, any information posted in these areas. Please note that whenever you post personal information in public areas such as message boards, that information can be collected and used by people you don't know.

**E-mail Correspondence**

We may provide on this Web site an online form or e-mail address to which visitors can send us questions or comments, or which visitors can use to request customer support. In the process of receiving and responding to such requests, we may collect personal information about you, such as your e-mail address or any other personal data contained on the form or in the body of your e-mail message. By allowing you to send us these requests, we are not attempting to solicit personal information from you. We only use the information for the purpose of responding to your questions and/or comments or to provide customer support. In some cases, your message will be deleted immediately after we've completed responding to your inquiry; however, in many cases, hard copies of your requests may be kept on file for our records or for quality control purposes. 

No matter what method we use to collect information and no matter how we use that information, we will only collect the information deemed reasonably necessary to fulfill your online requests and our legitimate business objectives.

To the extent that any of the activities listed above collect both personal and demographic information, we may combine the information and store it in our database as one record. Combining data allows us to customize registrations in accordance with our members’ preferences, and tailor the notices we send and the content we provide in accordance with our members’ interests. 

We may use your email address to send you service related announcements that tell you about changes to our Privacy Policy (when necessary), new areas or features on our web site, changes to our online service or support policies, and other related changes. We may also use your personal and demographic information for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can constantly improve the online products and services we provide you and to better meet your needs. 

**What happens if I refuse to provide my personal information to PokéGym?**

To use and view some areas available on the PokéGym, you would need to register. However, to simply browse our web site and explore the many parts of our web sites, you do not need to give us any personal information. 

**Does PokéGym use cookies, track IP addresses, or use other passive means to collect information?**

**Cookies**  
We use cookies to improve the use and functionality of our web site. A "cookie" is a small file or record-keeping device that web sites often store on a user's computer, either for as long as the user's web browser remains open ("session cookie") or for future use on the web site ("persistent cookie"). Persistent cookies are used to remember your username and password (so that you don't have to login every time you visit our web site), to tell us that you have visited our web site before, and to otherwise capture information that would make your next visit to our web site more enjoyable. Although we do not use persistent cookies to collect personal information such as your name, we link information captured in a persistent cookie with personal information already collected about you. This allows us to identify who you are by your login user name whenever you visit our web site and therefore saves you the time of having to re-enter your login information. You can always disable cookies or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent to your computer, although doing so may affect the functionality of our web site. 

**IP Addresses**  
Through the use of log files (see below), PokéGym may collect your Internet Protocol (IP) address to troubleshoot technical concerns and to maintain website safety and security. For example, keeping track of IP addresses might help us investigate possible abuse or violation of terms of service for our Web site. An IP address is a numeric address (either dynamic or static) assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider every time you use the Internet. 

**Log Files**  
PokéGym may collect information in the form of logs - files that record website activity and gather statistics about web users' browsing habits. These entries help PokéGym determine (among other things) how many and how often users have visited our web site, which pages they've visited, and other similar navigational data. We also use the log file entries for our internal marketing and demographic studies, so we can constantly improve the online services we provide you. 

**Who is collecting my personal information and is it shared with anyone?**  
The information that you disclose on this Web site is collected by PokéGym and is used in accordance with the practices set forth above. In addition, any information that you post in a message becomes available to all persons who have access to view it. A breakdown of our data disclosure policies follows. Please note that we do not sell or rent our customers' personal information to third parties for commercial reasons. 

**Legal and Business Transfers**  
We may disclose personal information in the good faith belief that we are required to do so by law, including but not limited to, disclosure to law enforcement or other government officials in connection with an investigation of alleged or actual fraud, intellectual property infringements, or other activity that is illegal or may expose you or us to legal liability or in the good faith belief that disclosure is necessary to protect the safety or welfare of PokéGym participants. In addition to legal entities, we may cooperate with Pokémon USA Inc. investigations and may compare data with other internet sites or access providers in the investigation of illegal or improper activities of shared members, in order to protect the integrity of the PokéGym site and the safety of our members. We also reserve the right to share member information as we deem necessary and proper.

**What safeguards does PokéGym use to protect my personal information?**  
PokéGym systems use passwords and userids (screen names) to protect the confidentiality, security, and integrity of the personal information collected from or published by our Web site users (including children under 13). Please be sure to use a secure password when setting up your account. Do you use something that is easy to guess, such as “password” or “1111”. Direct access to your personal information is limited to staff who need the information to keep the web site under control. 

**Can I choose how my personal information is used?**  
If you do not want to receive e-mail or Private Messages from PokéGym, please opt-out from these services at the time of registration (using the check boxes provided under the preferences section). If you want to receive e-mail or Private Messages from us, you must opt-in to these services by using the check boxes provided under the preference sections at the time of registration. If you have opted-in and, at a later time, wish to opt-out, or if after completing the registration process you now wish to opt-in to a preference or otherwise change your preferences, please visit the "Edit Profile" section on our Web site (where you can modify your contact information and preferences after logging in) or contact us using the information provided below. 

**How can I access my personal information or my child's personal information?**  
If you wish to review, update, or delete any personal information that we may have collected about you, please visit the "Edit Profile" section on our Web site or contact us using the information provided below. 

**Parental Access/Control**  
If you are a parent that has given PokéGym permission to collect and store your child's information (for such purposes of Web site registration), you can do the following at any time: (1) view, correct, or request that we delete your child's personal information; (2) update the permissions you gave us on the original consent form; and/or (3) discontinue further use or collection of your child's personal information. To do so, please either:   
1\. Use the user name and password assigned to your child during or after the parental consent process to access our Edit Profile tool, where you can do many of the things stated above;   
2\. Print out, complete, and sign a second Parental Consent Form, with the updated information or your specific request.   
Please be advised that if you permit your child to register on our Web site, your child will have the ability to change his or her user name and/or password through the use of our Edit Profile tool (as described above).
